

# SOHEL AHMED **ANSARI**

FRONT-END DEVELOPER

+971564710320 sohel.ahmed.ansari@gmail.com Dubai

#### **SKILLS**

React Redux Knockout.Js **JQuery** Javascript (ES6) **HTML** CSS (Less) Nodejs Webpack Git Angularjs TypeScript

### WEBSITES & SOCIAL LINKS

Website:

https://sohelansari.com

Linkedin:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/sohela nsari

Stackoverflow:

https://stackoverflow.com/users/22

79116/shinobi

# **HOBBIES**

Video Games, Cooking, Travelling

#### **ABOUT ME**

Experienced in everything from converting designs into functional pages to setting up complex applications in modern frameworks.

Specialized in handling front-end development and dealing with UI and UX of anything that I work on. I am always interested to put my views on the look and feel of the product.

History of working effectively in agile environments. Disciplined and hardworking team player.

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### SENIOR PROGRAMMER

ONE.COM | DUBAI MAY 2016 - PRESENT

Working on front-end and backend development of Webshop

(https://www.one.com/en/webshop)

Front-end is implemented using Knockout.js, backend is in Node.js and database in PostgreSQL.

We are now gradually re-writing this in React.

#### My role includes:

- Developing pixel perfect UI from given design and making it functional in React
- Fixing bugs in existing Knockout.js code.
- Converting Knockout.js code to React.
- Writing handlers in backend which is in Node.js and familiar with writing queries in PostgreSQL.
- Have worked on integrating payments through Credit card, iDEAL and Giropay using Stripe
- Acting as the communicator between my team of 5 developers with me in Dubai and the Project Manager in Copenhagen.
- Responsible for keeping an eye on the progress of the Sprint and making sure that the product manager is informed about any changes in it.
- Follow scrum methodology and Agile Software Development strategy.

Technologies include: React, Knockout.js, Javascript, HTML5, CSS, NodeJS, **PostgreSQL** 

#### SENIOR PROGRAMMER

NEXSALES CORPORATION | MUMBAI NOV 2014 - APR 2016

Worked on front-end development of a web app VoiceReach used by BPO for reaching out to prospects for marketing.

It was a single page web application written in AngularJS 1.3

# My role included:

- Getting involved in feature discussions and giving inputs on the UI/UX.
- Developing in AngularJS which includes creating HTML templates, styling CSS, writing code for angular controller, directive and services.
- Integrating external angular directives and using it.
- Follow scrum methodology and Agile Software Development strategy.

Technologies include: HTML5, CSS, Javascript, AngularJS 1.3, Bootstrap, NodeJS

# SOFTWARE ENGINEERING SR. ANALYST

ACCENTURE | MUMBAI FEB 2014 - NOV 2014

Worked on front-end development of a retail company client. Work included making templates for given psds and making it functional. Making sure the page is responsive on all devices.

Technologies include: HTML5, Javascript, jQuery, Sass, Bootstrap, Handlebars, Backbone.js

## SENIOR PROGRAMMER

**EDUCATION** 

ZEUS SYSTEMS PVT. LTD. | MUMBAI JUL 2009 - JAN 2014

Worked on many e-learning products to help kids of different age groups learn Maths and Science.

Technologies include: HTML5, Javascript, jQuery, Backbone.js, ActionScript 3, Flash

M.H. SABOO SIDDIK COLLEGE OF ENGINEERING | MUMBAI 2009